<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thread on JavaIsland</title>
    <link>https://www.javai.net/tags/thread/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thread on JavaIsland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:24:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.javai.net/tags/thread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The use of Future in java</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-future-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-future-use/</guid>
      <description>The use of Future in java Future is an interface introduced in java 1.5 that can be used to get asynchronous results easily. This article will explain how to use Future through specific examples.
Creating Future As mentioned above, Future represents the result of asynchronous execution, which means that when the asynchronous execution is finished, the returned result will be saved in Future.
So when do we use Future? Generally speaking, when we execute a long-running task, using Future allows us to temporarily deal with other tasks, and then return the result when the long task is finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronized keywords in java concurrency</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-synchronized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 10:26:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-synchronized/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In a multi-threaded environment, we often encounter resource competition, such as multiple threads going to modify the same shared variable at the same time, it is necessary to perform some processing of the resource access method to ensure that only one thread accesses it at the same time.
Java provides the synchronized keyword to facilitate us to achieve the above operation.
Why synchronized Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example where we create a class that provides a setSum method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference between wait and sleep in java</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-wait-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 22:19:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-wait-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this post, we will discuss the difference between wait() and sleep() methods in java. And discuss how to use these two methods.
Difference between wait and sleep wait() is a native method defined in Object.
1  public final native void wait(long timeout) throws InterruptedException;   So every instance of the class can call this method. wait() can only be called in a synchronized block. It will release the lock put on the object when it is synchronized.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
