<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>threadpool on JavaIsland</title>
    <link>https://www.javai.net/tags/threadpool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in threadpool on JavaIsland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:57:29 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.javai.net/tags/threadpool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Better use of Java thread pool</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/thread-pool-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:57:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/thread-pool-tips/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article combines the JUC package provided by Doug Lea in JDK1.5 to understand the use of thread pools from the setting of thread pool size parameters, the creation of work threads, the recycling of idle threads, the use of blocking queues, task rejection strategies, thread pool Hook and other aspects, which involves some details including the choice of different parameters, different queues, different rejection strategies, the resulting The details include the different parameters, the different queues, the choice of different rejection strategies, the resulting impact and behavior, and for better use of the thread pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to estimate throughput and thread pool size</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/threadpool-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 17:35:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/threadpool-size/</guid>
      <description>Estimating Throughput Now there is a task which execution time is divided into 2 parts, the first part does math and the second part waits for IO. these two parts are called compute operation and wait operation.
So now we need to estimate the peak throughput that can be achieved by executing this task with the CPU at full power.
Then we need to know how much time it takes to execute this task, how much time is spent on the computation part and how much time is spent on the wait part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thread pool rejection policy</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/thread-pool-rejection-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 14:10:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/thread-pool-rejection-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Preface When it comes to java thread pools nothing is more familiar than the ExecutorService interface. jdk1.5 adds java.util.concurrent package under this api, which greatly simplifies the development of multi-threaded code. Whether you use FixedThreadPool or CachedThreadPool the implementation behind it is ThreadPoolExecutor. threadPoolExecutor is a typical product of cache pooling design, because the pool has a size, when the pool volume is not enough to carry, it involves a rejection policy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
