<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jvm on JavaIsland</title>
    <link>https://www.javai.net/tags/jvm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jvm on JavaIsland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 19:44:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.javai.net/tags/jvm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Java Class File Format Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-class-file-format-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 19:44:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-class-file-format-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Preface Learn jvm word code, you need to understand the way class is composed, this article explains the process of parsing the class file format in java method, I hope it can help you.
Class file specification The code that is compiled and executed by the Java virtual machine uses a platform-neutral (hardware- and operating system-independent). It is often (but not always) stored as a file, so this format is called the Class file format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of Volatile</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/volatile-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 16:01:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/volatile-application/</guid>
      <description>Memory Visibility Since the Java Memory Model (JMM) states that all variables are stored in main memory, and each thread has its own working memory (cache).
When a thread is working, it needs to copy the data from the main memory to the working memory. This way, any operation on the data is based on the working memory (which is more efficient) and cannot directly manipulate the data in the main memory or the working memory of other threads, and then flush the updated data to the main memory afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Startup Params</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/java-startup-params/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 19:42:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/java-startup-params/</guid>
      <description>Basic Format Run java -help to see the basic format and options
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8  [root@localhost ~]# java -help Usage: java [-options] class [args...] (execute class) or java [-options] -jar jarfile [args...] (execute jar file) Startup options are omitted [-options]: options [-options]: options [args...] : Passes a parameter to the main method   Standard options  -help / -? : output help information -version : output version information -classpath / -cp: class search path for directories and zip/jar files .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
