<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>java8 on JavaIsland</title>
    <link>https://www.javai.net/tags/java8/</link>
    <description>Recent content in java8 on JavaIsland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 16:43:35 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.javai.net/tags/java8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building an infinite stream in java 8</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202206/java-infinite-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 16:43:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202206/java-infinite-stream/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In java, we can convert a specific set into a stream, so in some cases, such as in a test environment, we need to construct a stream with a certain number of elements, how do we need to handle it?
Here we can construct an unlimited stream and then call the limit method to limit the number returned.
Basic use Let&amp;rsquo;s start with an example of using Stream.iterate to create an infinite Stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Father of Java: Don&#39;t Stick with Java 8</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-not-stick-java8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:26:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-not-stick-java8/</guid>
      <description>James Gosling, the father of Java, recently twitter that developers should abandon JDK 8 as soon as possible and opt for JDK 17 LTS, which brings huge improvements in every aspect.
But maybe the father of Java was just promoting Corretto, the OpenJDK distribution for his boss AWS. and he suggests that developers still using JDK 8 might consider using Corretto&amp;rsquo;s new version- -Includes all the latest updates and CVE defenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on upgrading from Java 8 to Java 11</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-jdk8-upgrade-jdk11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 20:21:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-jdk8-upgrade-jdk11/</guid>
      <description>Preface Although the latest version of Java has evolved to Java 18, most projects on the market are still using Java 8. Many people are apprehensive about upgrading their Java version because the Java API is not necessarily forward compatible from Java 8. Java 11 is the next long-supported version of Java 8, and there is no doubt that Java 11 is even better than Java 8. superior.
This article describes the code checking tools used to convert code from Java 8 to Java 11, as well as the problems you may encounter and suggestions for resolving them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
