<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>concurrent on JavaIsland</title>
    <link>https://www.javai.net/tags/concurrent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in concurrent on JavaIsland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:48:54 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.javai.net/tags/concurrent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use of CyclicBarrier in java concurrency</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202205/java-cyclicbarrier-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:48:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202205/java-cyclicbarrier-use/</guid>
      <description>Introduction CyclicBarrier is a thread-safe component introduced in java 5. It has the concept of a barrier, which is used to wait for all threads to finish executing before performing a specific operation.
If we have many threads and each thread computes some data, then we need to wait for all the threads to finish executing and then add up the data computed by each thread to the final result, then we can use CyclicBarrier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of CountDownLatch in java concurrency</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202205/java-countdownlatch-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:34:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202205/java-countdownlatch-use/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In java concurrency, it is very important to control access to shared variables, sometimes we also want to control the order of execution of concurrent threads, for example: wait for all threads to finish executing before executing another thread, or wait for all threads to be ready before starting the execution of all threads, This time we can use CountDownLatch.
CountDownLatch contains a counter that is placed in the QueuedSynchronizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better use of Java thread pool</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/thread-pool-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:57:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/thread-pool-tips/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article combines the JUC package provided by Doug Lea in JDK1.5 to understand the use of thread pools from the setting of thread pool size parameters, the creation of work threads, the recycling of idle threads, the use of blocking queues, task rejection strategies, thread pool Hook and other aspects, which involves some details including the choice of different parameters, different queues, different rejection strategies, the resulting The details include the different parameters, the different queues, the choice of different rejection strategies, the resulting impact and behavior, and for better use of the thread pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronized keywords in java concurrency</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-synchronized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 10:26:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-synchronized/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In a multi-threaded environment, we often encounter resource competition, such as multiple threads going to modify the same shared variable at the same time, it is necessary to perform some processing of the resource access method to ensure that only one thread accesses it at the same time.
Java provides the synchronized keyword to facilitate us to achieve the above operation.
Why synchronized Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example where we create a class that provides a setSum method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference between wait and sleep in java</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-wait-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 22:19:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/java-wait-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this post, we will discuss the difference between wait() and sleep() methods in java. And discuss how to use these two methods.
Difference between wait and sleep wait() is a native method defined in Object.
1  public final native void wait(long timeout) throws InterruptedException;   So every instance of the class can call this method. wait() can only be called in a synchronized block. It will release the lock put on the object when it is synchronized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of Volatile</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/volatile-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 16:01:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/volatile-application/</guid>
      <description>Memory Visibility Since the Java Memory Model (JMM) states that all variables are stored in main memory, and each thread has its own working memory (cache).
When a thread is working, it needs to copy the data from the main memory to the working memory. This way, any operation on the data is based on the working memory (which is more efficient) and cannot directly manipulate the data in the main memory or the working memory of other threads, and then flush the updated data to the main memory afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReentrantLock implementation principle</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/reentrantlock-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 16:30:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/reentrantlock-principle/</guid>
      <description>When using synchronize to do synchronization, lock acquisition and release are implicitly implemented by compiling and adding different machine instructions to achieve the principle.
 ReentrantLock is a class based on AbstractQueuedSynchronizer(AQS for short) implementation, this article analyzes the implementation principle of ReentrantLock, I hope it will be helpful to you.
ReentrantLock: a thread can still repeat the lock after it has obtained it, and will not appear to block itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principle of implementation of atomic operations</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/atomic-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 16:00:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/atomic-principle/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction Atomic means &amp;ldquo;the smallest particle that cannot be further divided&amp;rdquo;, and atomic operation means &amp;ldquo;an operation or series of operations that cannot be interrupted&amp;rdquo;. Implementing atomic operations on a multiprocessor becomes a bit complicated. In this article, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about how atomic operations are implemented on Intel processors and in Java.
2. Definition of Terms Compare and Swap CAS operations require two values to be entered, an old value (the value before the desired operation) and a new value, during which the old value is compared to the new value if it has not changed, and not exchanged if it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thread pool rejection policy</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/thread-pool-rejection-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 14:10:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202204/thread-pool-rejection-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Preface When it comes to java thread pools nothing is more familiar than the ExecutorService interface. jdk1.5 adds java.util.concurrent package under this api, which greatly simplifies the development of multi-threaded code. Whether you use FixedThreadPool or CachedThreadPool the implementation behind it is ThreadPoolExecutor. threadPoolExecutor is a typical product of cache pooling design, because the pool has a size, when the pool volume is not enough to carry, it involves a rejection policy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
