<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on JavaIsland</title>
    <link>https://www.javai.net/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on JavaIsland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 19:16:46 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.javai.net/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring Framework RCE, Early Announcement</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/spring-framework-rce-early-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 19:16:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/spring-framework-rce-early-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Updates:
 [15:40 BST] Spring Boot 2.6.6 is available. [14:38 BST] Spring Boot 2.5.12 is available. [14:00 BST] CVE-2022-22965 is published. [13:03 BST] Added section &amp;ldquo;Misconceptions&amp;rdquo;. [12:34 BST] Added section &amp;ldquo;Am I Impacted&amp;rdquo;. [12:11 BST] Fix minor issue in the workaround for adding disallowedFields . [11:59 BST] Spring Framework versions 5.3.18 and 5.2.20 , which address the vulnerability, are now available. The release process for Spring Boot is in progress.  Overview I would like to announce an RCE vulnerability in the Spring Framework that was leaked out ahead of CVE publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle cracks down on Java licensing issues, enterprises remove JDK overnight</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/oracle-java-license/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 13:04:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/oracle-java-license/</guid>
      <description>According to a report in the foreign media The Register and feedback from major enterprises, Oracle has recently begun to include Java in its software licensing review, with the aim of Oracle&amp;rsquo;s move is an effort to push companies to pay, an operation it routinely employs to boost payment rates.
Oracle introduced two licensing models for Java SE. In April 2019, Oracle began charging a license fee for Java that was previously free, which requires users to pay for a subscription to a commercial Java SE product in order to receive patches and updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Spring Core Spring Beans Remote Code Warning Notice for Execution 0day Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/spring-0day-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 10:06:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/spring-0day-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Information indicates that an RCE 0day vulnerability has been reported in the Spring Framework. If the target system is developed using Spring and has a JDK version above JDK9, an unauthorized attacker can exploit this vulnerability to remotely execute arbitrary code on the target device.
1. Vulnerability Situation Analysis The Spring framework is the most widely used lightweight open source framework for Java, and in the JDK9 version of the Spring framework (and above), a remote attacker can obtain an AccessLogValve object through the framework&amp;rsquo;s parameter binding feature and use malicious field values to trigger the pipeline mechanism and write to a file in an arbitrary path if certain conditions are met.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JDK 18 / Java 18 GA is released</title>
      <link>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/jdk18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 22:44:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.javai.net/post/202203/jdk18/</guid>
      <description>JDK 18 / Java 18 GA is released. JDK 18 is a short-term maintenance release that will receive six months of support. Despite this, it is still available for use in production environments. According to the development plan, JDK 19 will be released this September, and the next LTS version, JDK 21, will be released in September 2023.
JDK 18 includes a total of nine JEPs, as well as hundreds of smaller enhancements and more than a thousand bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
